Cyst is a horror, science fiction, comedy film directed by Tyler Russell.
In the 1960s, a nurse's last day on her job is ruined when a doctor
inadvertently creates a cyst monster that terrorizes the office.
Patricia, played by Eva Habermann.
Dr. Guy, played by George Hardy.
Bill, played by Greg Sestero.
Al, played by Jason Douglas.
Mr. Sherman, played by Gene Jones.
Preston, played by Darren Ewing.
Tarlov cysts, also known as perineural cysts, are cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)-filled lesions that most commonly develop in the
sacral region of the spinal canal (S1–S5), and less frequently in the cervical, thoracic, or lumbar spine.
These cysts form as dilations of the nerve root sheath near the dorsal root ganglion,
specifically within the perineural space between the endoneurium and perineurium.
A defining feature is that the cyst walls contain nerve fibers,
which often line the inner cavity of the cyst itself.
This involvement of neural elements distinguishes Tarlov cysts from other extradural
meningeal cysts, such as meningeal diverticula, which do not contain nerve fibers.
The etiology of these cysts is not well understood; some current theories explaining this phenomenon include increased spinal fluid
pressure, filling of congenital cysts with one-way valves, and/or inflammation in response to trauma and disease.
They are named after an American neurosurgeon Isadore
Tarlov, who described them in 1938.
These cysts are often detected incidentally during MRI or
CT scans for other medical conditions.
They are also observed using magnetic resonance neurography with
communicating subarachnoid cysts of the spinal meninges.
Cysts with diameters of 1cm or larger are more likely to be symptomatic; although
cysts of any size may be symptomatic dependent on location and etiology.
Some 40% of patients with symptomatic Tarlov cysts can
associate a history of trauma or childbirth.
Current treatment options include CSF aspiration, Aspiration and Fibrin Glue Injection (AFGI),
laminectomy with wrapping of the cyst, among other surgical treatment approaches.
Interventional treatment of Tarlov cysts is the only means by which symptoms might
permanently be resolved due to the fact that the cysts often refill after aspiration.
Tarlov cysts often enlarge over time, especially if
the sac has a check valve type opening.
They are differentiated from other meningeal and arachnoid cysts because they are innervated
and diagnosis can in cases be demonstrated with subarachnoid communication.
Tarlov perineural cysts have occasionally been observed in patients with connective tissue
disorders such as Marfan syndrome, Ehlers–Danlos syndrome, and Loeys–Dietz syndrome.
The film explores themes of monster, mad doctor, schlock, surgery gone wrong.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.